(新八)銀さん！
何？
そう｡
今日は 頼まれてません｡
(銀時)え～ ﾃﾚﾋﾞ東京さんから
大事なお知らせで～す｡
Well, I've got an important announcement from TV Tokyo.
The current analog broadcast will be ending on July 24, 2011 and switching
to a terrestrial digital broadcast.
Once that has happened, analog televisions will...
Gin-san.
What?
They didn't ask for this today.
Really?
Shuddap...
やっぱこの ﾍﾟﾛ～ﾝっちゅうのが
ええじゃろ？
This Perowne stuff is good.
ﾍﾟﾛ～ﾝは 確かにいいわな！
Can't deny that.
You'll take anything, huh?
♪♪～
(長谷川)ﾏﾀﾞｵとよばれて
はや数年｡
After all these years of being called DORK,
Gin-san, I'm gonna do it.
銀さん ｵﾚはやるぜ！
くすぶり続けたｵﾚの人生｡
裏目を引き続ける負の連鎖｡
A life that keeps sputtering on...
An endless loop of finding bad things on the other side...
ﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙから
今日こそ脱出してやるぜ！
I'm going to break free of this DORK Spiral today!
そうよ！ 人生なんて➡
That's right.
All you need is a chance to turn your life around.
ふとしたきっかけで
変わるもんさ！
We'll be taking off from this place today.
今日 この場所から
ｵﾚたちは羽ばたく！
Let's go, Hasegawa-san.
いくぜ！ 長谷川さん！
おう！
Yeah!
勝って 勝って
勝ちまくって➡
Win, win, and win more!
脱 ﾏﾀﾞｵだ～!!
No more DORK!
["The other side of the other side of the other side would be the other side."]
競馬とは 思考のｹﾞｰﾑ｡
Horse racing is a mind game.
さまざまな要素が絡み合い
それが結果となる｡
The result comes from a number of intertwined factors.
はっきり言って
考えないﾔﾂは ﾊﾞｶだ｡
Quite frankly, anybody who doesn't use their head is an idiot.
詳しいことは わからねえが
要するに➡
I don't understand the nitty-gritty stuff,
but you just have to pick the winning horse, right?
勝つ馬を当てりゃいいんだろ？
あまいな｡
Too naive.
(長谷川)成績 展開 持ち時計
調教 血統 騎手 調教師のｺﾒﾝﾄ｡
There are notes about records, news, times, training, pedigrees, jockeys, trainers...
ここに書かれている
さまざまな情報をもとに➡
The wealth of information written here narrows down the choices.
買い目を絞り込んでいく｡
勿論 文面どおりには
受け取らない｡
Naturally, you can't take what's written at face value.
You have to read between the lines to spot the hidden signs and arrive at the only possible truth.
裏の裏まで
しっかりと読みつくし➡
そこに隠されたｻｲﾝをひもとき➡
たったひとつの
真実をつかみ取る｡
それが予想という…｡
って 長えよ！
That's how you predict...
God, that's long!
That's a long-ass explanation!
説明 長えよ！
I'm a beginner, so I don't understand all that crap.
こっちは初心者なんだから
よく わかんねえっつうの！
つまり どの馬がくるんだ!?
どの馬が！
So which horse has it coming? Which horse is it?
だからぁ それを予想するのが
競馬の醍醐味でしょうが！
Like I was saying, the predicting is the epitome of horse racing!
If you think it's too much effort, just go with your gut!
面倒くさいなら
直感で決めたらいいんじゃね!?
There's always beginner's luck.
ﾋﾞｷﾞﾅｰｽﾞﾗｯｸってのもあるんじゃね!?
なるほど 直感ねぇ｡
I see. Go with my gut...
♪♪～
って ｵｲ！ 何それ 日付!?
Hey! What's that?!
The date?!
そんなんで勝てるんなら
苦労しねえよ！
It wouldn't be so hard if you could win like that!
大丈夫だって！
Don't worry.
Weren't you talking about beginner's luck just now?
ｱﾝﾀさっき ﾋﾞｷﾞﾅｰｽﾞﾗｯｸって
言ったじゃん｡
The stars are aligned for me today.
ｵﾚは今日
星まわりがいいんだよ｡
I can see the star of victory shining above me.
勝利の星が
頭上に輝いて見えんだよ｡
だって ほら ｱﾝﾀにも見えるだろ？
Yeah, can't you see that shining star next to the Big Dipper?
あの北斗七星の横に輝く星が！
No, you don't want to see that one.
いや あれ見えたら
まずいやつだから！
あれ見えて
死んじゃった人いるからね！
People have died after seeing that.
(ﾌｧﾝﾌｧｰﾚ)
(長谷川)おっかしいな…｡
目のつけどころは➡
That's odd...
I had a pretty good feeling this time...
よかったんだけどな｡
おっかしいな…｡
That's odd...
目のつけどころは
よかったんだけどよ｡
I had a pretty good feeling this time...
…って 銀さんのは
予想じゃないから｡
Wait, you weren't even predicting anything.
You just went with the date.
日付で決めてただけだから！
ｱﾝﾀに言われたくねえよ！
You're one to talk.
ｵﾒｴさんの馬券も
かすりもしてねえだろ！
Your ticket was completely wrong, too.
いや 一緒にしないでくれよ！
No, don't lump me together with you.
My prediction was on a whole different scale from yours.
ｵﾚのと ｱﾝﾀの予想じゃ
過程が全然 違う｡
I stayed up for seven hours last night simulating possible outcomes.
こちとら 昨日の晩から
寝ないで計７時間➡
あらゆる展開を
ｼﾐｭﾚｰｼｮﾝしてきたんだ｡
And that lead to this result.
その予想の結果が これだ｡
Hey, don't you feel empty when you say that?
おい 言ってて
むなしくならねえの？ それ…｡
How much time are you wasting?
どんだけ時間ﾑﾀﾞにしてんだよ｡
つうか 他にやることなかったの？
And yeah, didn't you have anything else to do?
ないよ｡
I didn't.
ごめんなさい｡
I'm sorry.
ま… まあ 気を取り直して
もう１ﾚｰｽいこうぜ 長谷川さん｡
W-Well, let's pull ourselves together and try another race, Hasegawa-san.
そうだよな！ たかだか
１ﾚｰｽ負けただけだもんな｡
You're right.
We only lost one race.
The game's just begun!
勝負は これからだってぇの！
おうよ！
That's right!
(歓声)
♪♪～
Go! Go!
いけ～！ いけいけ～!!
あぁ～!!
♪♪～
That's it! Run your ass off!
そこだ～！ いけ お前！
走れ！ ﾑﾁ！ ﾑﾁ入れろ!!
The whip! Use the whip!
♪♪～
全敗だ…｡
Lost everything...
Yeah...
ああ… ｹﾂの毛まで
むしられちまった｡
Even had the hairs on my ass plucked off...
I don't even have enough for the train-ride back.
もう電車賃すら残ってねえ｡
ﾍｯ… ﾍﾍﾍﾍ｡
どうした？ 負けが込んで
おかしくなったか？
What's wrong?
Did you snap after losing so much.
いや なんかｵﾚ ｱﾝﾀと出会ってから
こんなんばっかだったなぁって｡
Nah.
It just seems like this is how it's always been since we met.
そうだっけ？
Really?
'Cause you know, I may be like this now,
だってよ 銀さんたちと出会う前は
今は こんなｵﾚでも➡
but before I met y'all, I was a top level bureaucrat in the Bakufu.
幕府の高級官僚だったんだぜ｡
♪♪～
Weren't you ever taught to obey authority?
((お上の言うことには
逆らうな とは➡
教わらなかったか？
ｵﾒｴら 幕府の…｡
You're from the Bakufu?
入国管理局の者だ｡
We're from Immigration.
ｱﾝﾀに仕事の依頼に来た｡
万事屋さん))
We've got a job for you, Odd Jobs.
出世街道 ばく進してたんだよ｡
これでも｡
I was shooting my way up the ladder...
Despite appearances...
だけど…｡
But...
Gin-san!
((銀さ～ん!!
新八！
Shinpachi!
あっ！
勝手なﾏﾈするなって
言ってるでしょ！
I told you not to act arbitrarily!
It's gonna eat me!
ﾃﾒｴ…｡
Bastard...
無傷で捕獲なんざぁ
不可能なのは百も承知だよ｡
I'm fully aware that we won't be able to capture it in one piece.
多少の犠牲が出なきゃ
ﾊﾞｶ皇子は わかんないんだって｡
A little sacrifice is necessary for the stupid prince to understand that fact.
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
ちょっと！ 聞いてんの!?
あれの処分許可得るために
ｳﾁの助手 ｴｻにするってか…｡
So you want to use my sidekick as bait so you can get permission to dispose of that?
どうやら ﾃﾒｴら
ﾎﾝﾄに腐っちまってるみてぇだな｡
You people are rotten to the core.
Like I said, we have to learn to live with them.
言ったろ？ ｵﾚたちは ﾔﾂらと
共生していくしかないんだってば｡
腐ってようが ｵﾚは ｵﾚのやり方で
国を守らせてもらう｡
Rotten or not, I'm protecting this country in my own way.
それが ｵﾚなりの武士道だ｡
That's my kind of samurai code.
ﾌｯ… そうかい｡
I see.
ん？
じゃあ ｵﾚは ｵﾚの武士道で➡
Then, I'll follow my own samurai code!
いかせてもらう!!
待て！
Wait up!
幕府が滅ぼうが
国が滅ぼうが関係ねえ！
So what if the Bakufu or the country collapses?!
あっ!?
ｵﾚは 自分の肉体が滅ぶまで➡
I'll live tall until the day this body falls apart!
背筋伸ばして 生きてくだけよ!!
(新八たち)あっ！
♪♪～
《あ～ めちゃくちゃ
やってくれやがって あの野郎》
That bastard's gone and done it.
長谷川！ どういうことだ！
Hasegawa, what is the meaning of this?!
(ﾊﾀ皇子)無傷で捕らえよと
申したはずじゃ！
I told you to capture him without hurting him!
どう責任とってくれるか！
国際問題じゃ これは！
This is an international issue!
Live tall...
《背筋を伸ばして生きる｡
まるで ｶﾞｷの学級目標じゃねえか｡
Sounds like a goal a kid would set.
そういや
おふくろもよく言ってたな｡
That's right. My mother used to say...
｢背中曲がってるぞ｡
しゃんと立て｣って｡
"You're hunched over. Stand up straight."
Mom, am I standing up straight right now?
母ちゃん ｵﾚ
今まっすぐ立てているか？》
長谷川！ 今回の件は 父上に
報告させてもらうぞよ 長谷川！
-gawa!
Hasegawa!
I'm going to report this incident to my father!
Shut it.
せ～よ！
Shut it!
うるせえよ！ うるせえって
言ってんだよ このﾎﾟﾁﾀﾏ星人！))
I told you to shut your mouth, you blob-headed alien!
あそこから
すべては おかしくなっちまった｡
That was where everything started going wrong.
それまでｵﾚは
長谷川泰三だったんだよ｡
Before that point, I was Taizo Hasegawa.
ちゃんとした名前で呼ばれてたさ｡
People called me by my real name.
だけど あんときからｵﾚは｡
But ever since...
((神楽:おじちゃんは どうして
仕事ｸﾋﾞになっちゃったの？
Why were you fired, old-timer?
う～ん それはね いっときの
ﾃﾝｼｮﾝに身を任せたからだよ｡
Well... Because...
It's because I lost my head once and just followed my bliss.
お嬢ちゃんも若いからって 後先
考えずに 行動しちゃいけないよ｡
A young girl like you should always think about the consequences of your actions.
人生ってのは 長いんだから｡
Life is long, you know.
ｵﾒｴに言われたくねえよ！
負け組が！
I don't want to hear that from a loser like you.
じゃあな まるでﾀﾞﾒなｵｯｻﾝ！
See ya, you Dumb Old Retarded Kook!
Or "DORK" for short!
略して ﾏﾀﾞｵ))
そうｵﾚは
ﾏﾀﾞｵになっちまったんだ｡
Yes...
I became DORK...
Hasegawa-san...
長谷川さん 帰ろうぜ｡
終わったんだよ｡
Let's go...
Our battle's over now...
ｵﾚたちの闘いはもう｡
振り返ってみりゃ ｵﾚたち２人で
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙに勝ったためしがねえ｡
Looking back, the two of us have never come out ahead when we gamble together.
When we play pachinko, we end up losing the money for the next day's meals...
ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺすりゃ 明日の食費まで失い｡
ｶｼﾞﾉに行きゃ…｡
When we go to the casino...
Everybody's ready?
((どちらさまも ようござんすね｡
ﾊｰｯ！
(２人)丁！))
Even!
身ぐるみはがされる始末だ｡
We leave without the clothes on our backs.
もう いいじゃねえか｡
Enough already...
銀さん
今日ばっかりは わけが違うんだ｡
Gin-san, today's different.
明日は ﾊﾂの誕生日なんだ｡
Tomorrow is Hatsu's birthday.
そうか ｶﾐさんの｡
I see... Your wife's...
こんなんになっちまった
今でも やっぱりﾊﾂの➡
Even after everything that's happened,
I still want to look good for Hatsu.
ｱｲﾂの前では
まだかっこつけたくてよ｡
まあ ﾀﾞﾒながらもなんとか
やってる夫 くらいには➡
Well, I at least want to be a husband who manages to scrape by,
despite being a failure.
いときてえんだよ ｵﾚは｡
そう思って
今までだってあがいてきた｡
That's what's kept me floundering around this whole time.
I worked my ass off to find a job.
なんとか定職につこうと
いろいろがんばってきたよ｡
I struggled in vain to escape this lifestyle.
この生活から抜け出そうと
必死に悪あがきしてきたさ｡
だが 結果はいつも失敗｡
But my efforts always ended in failure...
これが ﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙってやつか｡
Is this the DORK Spiral?
Now, I don't even have a place to live, let alone a job.
今となっては 定職どころが
定住すら持たなくなる始末｡
Er, wait.
…って あれ？
今 振り返ると➡
Looking back now, all of my failures were because of you guys...
ｵﾚの失敗してきた原因って
全部 銀さんたちのせい…｡
気のせいだ｡
It's just your imagination.
はぁ…｡
ﾊﾂとは ちょくちょく電話じゃ
連絡とってるが➡
I talk to Hatsu every now and then on the phone,
直接会ったのは
あの裁判のときが最後だ｡
but the trial was the last time I saw her in person.
Sorry.
((すまねえな ｺｲﾂ また
ｱﾝﾀの用意したｽｰﾂ着なかったよ｡
He didn't wear the suit you prepared.
とんでもねえ ｶﾞﾝｺ野郎だ｡
What a stubborn bastard.
いや とんでもねえｶﾞﾝｺ夫婦か｡
Or no, what a stubborn couple.
汚ねえ格好同士 お似合いだぜ｡
You're perfect for each other in those dirty clothes.
《ﾊﾂ》
Hatsu...
詮議のほどを言い渡す｡
I will now deliver the committee's verdict.
被告人 長谷川泰三を
有罪とする｡
The accused, Taizo Hasegawa,
is found guilty.
女房を泣かせた罪だ｡
Of the crime of making his wife cry.
今すぐ
あの女を追ってくがいいや｡
Go after her right away.
それが ｵﾒｴさんの刑だ｡
(長谷川)お奉行！
That's your sentence.
Magistrate!
なお 破牙検事は 詳しい事情を
聞き次第 処分を下す｡
As for D.A. Haga, we shall punish him accordingly once we've learned the details.
被告人が所持していたＤＶＤは
危険物とみなし➡
The DVDs in the possession of the accused have been deemed a dangerous substance,
私が預かることとする｡
so I shall take custody of them personally.
Why?!
なんでだよ！
どんだけＤＶＤ観てえんだよ！
How badly do you want to watch those DVDs?!
これにて一件落着｡
And so, this case is closed.
Hatsu!
ﾊﾂ！ ちょっと…
ちょっと待ってくれ 話を…｡
Wait! Hold on!
I need to tell you something!
うおぉ～！
やりましたね 長谷川さん｡
You did it, Hasegawa-san!
DORK! We'll get your compensation for you!
ﾏﾀﾞｵ 報酬は ちゃんともらうから｡
Hatsu!
ﾊﾂ！
本当に ｱｲﾂには
苦労のかけっぱなしで｡
I've made her suffer so much...
I want to at least buy her a present.
せめて ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄの１つも
買ってやりてえと思ってよ｡
ﾊﾊｯ 笑っちまうだろ？
笑えよ｡
Makes you wanna laugh, right?
Go ahead.
すべて こぼれ落ちちまった｡
Everything's fallen apart.
ﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙのせいで
仕事も金も➡
Thanks to the DORK Spiral, I have no job, no money... I have nothing left...
ｵﾚの手には もう何も残ってねえ｡
でもよ それでも ｵﾚは
引き下がるわけにはいかねえよ｡
Still...
I can't back down.
銀さんは帰っていいぜ｡
You can go home, Gin-san.
これ以上
無理強いはできねえからな｡
I can't force you to stay here any longer.
だが ｵﾚは…｡
帰れだ？
But, I...
Go home?
冗談じゃねえ｡
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm finally getting the hang of it.
こちとら ようやく
ｺﾂがつかめてきたところよ｡
銀さん…｡
Gin-san...
やろうぜ 最後まで｡
We're staying to the end.
見届けてやるよ ｱﾝﾀの闘い｡
I'll watch your battle all the way through.
ｵﾚは あきらめねえ！
I won't give up.
As long as there's a 1% chance...
可能性が
１％でも残っているかぎり➡
ﾊﾟﾝﾂが１枚でも
残っているかぎり！
As long as I still have my underwear...
ﾊﾂのために
ｵﾚたちの未来のために➡
I'll break free of this DORK Spiral, for Hatsu... For our future!
絶対に このﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙを
打ち破ってみせる｡
泣いても笑っても
これで最後だ｡
Whether you like it or not, this is the last shot.
後悔のないようにな｡
Make sure you have no regrets.
銀さん｡
長谷川さんよ｡
Gin-san...
Hasegawa-san...
(２人)勝負じゃ！
It's on!
そう 博打とは
何を賭けるかが問題なんだ｡
Yes...
When gambling, the question is what you bet.
どんなﾘｽｸを背負うかによって
その代価はさまざまだ｡
The cost varies depending on the risk.
金を賭け 自らの身を➡
The fleeting thrill of betting money and putting yourself on the line...
削ることによって得られる
刹那的なｽﾘﾙ｡
馬や騎手へと感情移入することに
よって得られる 感動や挫折｡
The ardor and frustration from empathizing with the horse and jockey...
賭けるものは 人によって違う｡
Different people bet different things.
だが ｵﾚは…｡
But I
この馬に ｵﾚの人生を賭ける！
will bet my life on this horse!
13の単勝 全部｡
Everything on number 13 winning!
はいよ｡ 13番に 300円と…｡
Gotcha.
300 yen on number 13.
(ﾌｧﾝﾌｧｰﾚ)
[ﾏｲｸ]本日の最終ﾚｰｽ
ｻﾗ1,000万条件の古馬混合戦｡
Today's final race is made up of older horses with a ten million yen earnings limit.
[ﾏｲｸ]芝1,800ﾒｰﾄﾙ
ﾌﾙｹﾞｰﾄ16頭で行われます｡
The race will be 1800 meters on turf with all sixteen gates occupied.
[ﾏｲｸ]枠入りは順調
次々と ｹﾞｰﾄに入っていきます｡
The horses are entering their gates one by one without any incident.
頼むぞ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ…｡
I'm counting on you, Justaway...
お前の爆発力に すべてを賭ける！
I'm staking everything on your explosive speed!
[ﾏｲｸ]さあ 最後に
ﾋﾞｻﾞﾉﾊﾟﾃｯｸが入りました｡ ｹﾞｰﾄｲﾝ完了｡
Finally, Patek of Visa has entered its gate.
All horses in.
[ﾏｲｸ]ｽﾀｰﾄしました｡
まずまず きれいなｽﾀｰﾄ｡
The race has begun.
A clean start.
[ﾏｲｸ]各馬 ﾎﾟｼﾞｼｮﾝ争いに移ります｡
The horses are now battling for position.
[ﾏｲｸ]まずは
何がいきますでしょうか？
Who will have the early advantage?
In front, we have Arcade Humming.
[ﾏｲｸ]先頭は ｹﾞｰｾﾝﾊﾐﾝｸﾞ｡
３番手には ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ持ったまま｡
Cheap Impact is holding its position at third.
[ﾏｲｸ]人気のﾎﾞﾉﾏｰﾁｬﾝは まだ
中段のうち目に控えています｡
Bono Machan is in the middle of the pack.
(歓声)
《ﾊﾂよ… この勝負に勝てば
ｵﾚは 変われそうな気がする｡
Hatsu...
I have a feeling I can change if I win this race...
ﾊﾂ！》
Hatsu!
[ﾏｲｸ]先頭は 相変わらずｹﾞｰｾﾝﾊﾐﾝｸﾞ｡
Arcade Humming is still in front.
[ﾏｲｸ]後続が 徐々に徐々に
先頭集団へと距離をつめて➡
The trailers are slowly cutting down on his lead.
各馬 ﾀﾞﾝｺﾞ状態のまま
３ｺｰﾅｰから ４ｺｰﾅｰへ｡
They've just turned the third corner and are on their way to the fourth.
《いや ｵﾚは
変わらなければならないんだ｡
No, I have to change...
ﾊﾂのためにも 勝って 勝って
ｵﾚは変わるんだ！》
For Hatsu's sake, I have to win! Win and change!
[ﾏｲｸ]今 第４ｺｰﾅｰを回って
直線に向きました｡
They've turned the fourth corner and hit the last stretch.
[ﾏｲｸ]先頭は ｹﾞｰｾﾝﾊﾐﾝｸﾞ｡
外から ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄが並びかける！
Arcade Humming in front.
Cheap Impact bearing down from the outside.
《銀さん 応援してくれるよな？
ｵﾚとﾊﾂが…》
Gin-san, you're rooting for Hatsu and me, right?
いけ！ ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ!!
えっ!?
Go! Cheap Impact!
[ﾏｲｸ]かわした！ かわした！
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ 先頭!!
He's pulled ahead! It's Cheap Impact!
よし！
ちょ… ちょっ…｡
Aw, yeah!
Uh, wait. What are you doing, Gin-san?!
どういうことだよ 銀さん!?
最後まで見届けるとか➡
You said you'd watch my battle all the way through!
かっこいいこと言ってたじゃん！
ああ 見届けてやるさ｡
Yeah, I will.
だがよ
ｵﾚにはｵﾚの勝負があんだよ！
But I have my own battle going on at the same time.
いけ！ そのまま突っ込め!!
おかしいよ！ ずりいよ!!
Go! All the way through!
That's wrong! And dishonest!
それでも主人公!?
And you're supposed to be the main character?!
Exactly!
ｲｸﾞｻﾞｸﾄﾘｰ！ 主役だからこそ
勝負には勝たなくちゃならねえ｡
As the main character, I have to win my battles!
これが たったひとつの
冴えたやり方｡
えっ!?
This was the method I arrived at!
考えてもみろ｡ ｱﾝﾀは
重度のﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙに陥っている｡
Think about it.
You're falling down a serious DORK Spiral.
ｿｲﾂが どんなに予想しようが➡
It didn't matter what your prediction was.
すべて裏目 裏目に
なっちまうんだからな｡
The result would always be another step ahead.
だから ｵﾚは賭けたんだ｡
ｱﾝﾀの その裏目っぷりにな｡
So I decided to bet
on your tendency to have things backfires.
ど… どういうこと？
Wh-What does that mean?
ｱﾝﾀが 真っ先に消した馬
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄに➡
I bet everything on the horse you crossed out first, Cheap Impact.
ｵﾚのすべてを ぶち込んだ｡
恨むなよ｡ 今までのように➡
Don't hold a grudge.
I'm sick of losing everything with you when we gamble together!
ｷﾞｬﾝﾌﾞﾙで ｱﾝﾀと共倒れするﾊﾟﾀｰﾝは
もう飽きた｡
今度は ｱﾝﾀを踏み台にして
ｵﾚは 勝ち組の仲間入りじゃ!!
This time, I'll use you as a stepping stone
to become a winner!
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ｡
ﾊﾊ…｡
Gin-san, you've forgotten one critical thing.
銀さん ｱﾝﾀは ひとつ
大きなことを見落としてるぜ｡
あん？
I'm not the only one who suffers from the DORK Spiral backfiring.
すべてが裏目のﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙに
飲み込まれてるのは➡
ｵﾚだけじゃねえ｡
銀さん ｱﾝﾀもだ！
Gin-san, it's the same for you!
何 負け惜しみ 言ってんの？
現に ｵﾚが買った馬は先頭を…｡
You're such a poor loser.
Look at how my horse is leading...
[ﾏｲｸ]後続は どうか？
ﾋｹﾞﾐﾗｸﾙが 内から➡
Where are the others?
Bearded Miracle is coming from the inside.
そして外を回って
きた きた！ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ!!
Making a run on the outside is
Justaway!
[ﾏｲｸ]ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲが 一気に差をつめる！
Justaway has closed the gap!
Incredible speed!
[ﾏｲｸ]ものすごい足！
爆発的な二の足だ!!
What explosive speed!
きた きた！
きた きた きた きた!!
Here it comes!
なに!?
What?!
Gin-san, this is no longer an ordinary horse race.
銀さん ｺｲﾂは もう
ただの競馬じゃねえ｡
ﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙ脱出を賭けた➡
It's the DORK Cup's final match to determine if I can escape this DORK Spiral!
いや これからの人生を賭けた
最強のﾏﾀﾞｵ決定戦だ！
Go, Justaway!
いけ～ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ
ｺﾞｰｲﾝｸﾞ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ！
Cross the line, Justaway!
Escape, Cheap Impact!
逃げろ ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ！
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲから ﾗﾝﾅｳｪｲ！
Run away from Justaway!
[ﾏｲｸ]先頭は ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ！
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄ ３馬身のﾘｰﾄﾞ｡
Cheap Impact is in front!
Cheap Impact has a three length lead.
[ﾏｲｸ]追いつめるのは ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ
残りは あと200！
Justaway is closing in!
200 meters to go!
そのまま そのまま！
Keep going! Keep going! Keep going! Keep going!
させ させ させ させ～!!
Pass him! Pass him! Pass him! Pass him!
Will it be Cheap Impact?
[ﾏｲｸ]ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
Or Justaway?
Cheap Impact or Justaway?
[ﾏｲｸ]並んだ 並んだ
壮絶な叩きあい！
They're neck and neck!
An epic match!
Please! Please! Please! Please!
お願いします お願いします
お願いします お願いします！
む～！
Cheap Impact?!
[ﾏｲｸ]ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
Justaway?!
Cheap Impact or Justaway?!
♪♪～
[ﾏｲｸ]ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
Cheap Impact?! Justaway?!
Cheap Impact or Justaway?!
(２人)うぬ～！
[ﾏｲｸ]ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
ﾁｰﾌﾟｲﾝﾊﾟｸﾄか ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲか？
Cheap Impact?! Justaway?!
Justaway breaks ahead and they cross the finish line!
[ﾏｲｸ]わずかに ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ
さしきったところで ｺﾞｰﾙｲﾝ！
[ﾏｲｸ]勝ったのは ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ！
Justaway has won!
ああ…｡
き きた とうとうきた｡
H-Here it comes...
Finally, it's come...
あ～!! ったく
やってられるかよ こんﾁｸｼｮｳ！
Man! I can't take this anymore!
Damn it! Damn it! I demand a do over!
このﾔﾛｰ このﾔﾛｰ やり直せ!!
やった やったよ銀さん｡
I did it...
I did it, Gin-san...
ｵﾚ これで 脱ﾏﾀﾞｵｽﾊﾟｲﾗﾙ
これで ﾏﾀﾞｵ卒業だ｡
I've finally escaped the DORK Spiral...
I can finally graduate from being DORK...
ﾌｯ よかったじゃねえか｡
うん｡
Isn't that nice?
ﾊﾂ これでｵﾚは 胸を張って
お前に会いに…｡
Hatsu...
Now I can go see you with my head held high...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]大江戸競馬 第12ﾚｰｽは➡
A deliberation is being held regarding the fourth corner of Oedo Horse Race number 12.
４ｺｰﾅｰのできごとについて
審議を行います｡
(一同)おお!?
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]審議の結果 ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ号は
４ｺｰﾅｰで 急に外側へ斜行し➡
The result of the deliberation is that Justaway went outside the boundary
ﾎﾞﾉﾏｰﾁｬﾝ号の進路を妨害したとし
失格とします｡
at the fourth corner, blocking Bono Machan's path, and will be disqualified.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]繰り返します ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ号は…｡
Justaway went outside the boundary at the fourth corner...
なんだって!?
ｵﾚ よく聞こえなかったわ｡
Wh-What was that?
I couldn't hear what he said.
What does it say on the screen?
画面 どうなってる？
涙でくもって よく見えねえや｡
My eyes are all teared up, so I can't see clearly.
ってえことは…｡
Which means...
My ticket won!
ｵﾚの馬券 当ってんじゃねえか!!
What the hell is this?!
なんなんですか これ!!
ｵﾚが何したってえの？
What did I do to deserve this?
Why did this have to happen?!
どうしてこうなっちゃうの？
なんで ｵﾚが なんで…｡
Why me?! Why?!
Hasegawa-san, what is this?!
長谷川さん こりゃあ いったい…｡
♪♪～
[Suicide Note]
長谷川さ～ん!!
Hasegawa-san!
[Always remembered...]
死んでないからね!!
I'm not dead!
It's a gag anime, so I can't die!
ｷﾞｬｸﾞｱﾆﾒなんだから
死ぬわけないじゃん！
ったく ｵﾁがないから人殺すって
どういう神経してんだよ!!
God...
The staff is made up of a bunch of heartless bastards
who kill somebody off because they can't come up with a punch line!
ここのｽﾀｯﾌは!?
ｵｹﾗだって ﾐﾐｽﾞだって➡
Weren't you ever taught that crickets and worms
命は大事なんだからって
学ばなかった？
are still living creatures so you just treat them with care?!
[Always remembered...]
って しつけえよ!!
Hey! Give it up already!
[The End]
[Preview]
What? It's okay for me to bitch a bit?
Well, after three years, I've got a whole list of stuff to bitch about.
Even if I'm the main character of a JUMP series, I've got plenty of stuff to unload.
Actually, on second thought, I'm bitching all the time, so once you tell me to bitch,
I can't really think of anything.
["It Takes a Bit of Courage to Enter a Street Vendor's Stand"]
Hell, am I the only main character who bitches all the time?
[And the name of that stand is "Guchiriya."]
[Let's go vent all those pent-up complaints we've been saving every day.]
[See you next time.]